#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### PERSONAL INFO VO HONG TUAN LINH



- ₹ 588/37/26A, Huynh Tan Phat street, Tan Phu ward, District 7
- 0939 420 344
- tuanlinh.vh@gmail.com
- Skype tuanlinh\_vo

Sex Male | Date of birth 03/12/1989

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Experienced Data Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology-related industry. Skilled in Market Research, Social Listening, Social Media Analytics. Strong business development professional with a Bachelor's degree focused on International Business/Trade/Commerce.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### *Sep 2015 – Jun 2017*

#### DATA ANALYST - SDL TECHNOLOGIES VIETNAM

Business: Market Research.

Research American/European/Asian social media sites with required internal and external tools in order to build insightful reports to worldwide clients, which help improve their business decisions.

- Reporting on data includes:
  - Setup keywords, search strings based on clients' objectives to collect raw data
  - Filter, categorize and analyze the defined dataset using company's tools to derive insights.
  - State and test hypotheses that contribute to report body.
  - Determine when, where, what and why people talk about a brand/product on social media platforms (YouTube, Reddit, Flickr, Twitter, Instagram, Facebook, forums, blogs, etc...)
  - Determine sentiment of consumer voice.
  - Identify main themes of conversations using Topic Modeling function.
  - Identify key influencers.
  - Identify key trends in data sets.
  - Monitor client's social media accounts to keep crisis under control.
- Work with the Account team in support of Research & Data Managers to figure out clients' needs.
- Work with Back-end team to ensure improvement and innovation in capturing data.

#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

## Apr 2014 – Aug 2015 BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT – CIRCLE K VIETNAM

Business: Retail / Marketing

Promote Circle K brand by integrating various types of additional services into the franchise. Take responsibility for maintaining current services (laundry, ticketing, ATM, bill payment) as well as developing potential ones (food delivery, elottery...). Assist and report directly to Director of Marketing & Business Development the following tasks:

- Work on sourcing suppliers, building visibility and raising brand awareness.
- Liaise with suppliers to ensure marketing campaigns run effectively on both online and offline channels. Take care of POSM, articles and posts on websites, Facebook fan pages.
- Work cross-functionally with other departments: Operation, Training, Data Management... to ensure all information, guidelines are communicated well to all staff in stores when launching new marketing campaigns.
- Examine and assess possible locations to install ATM machines.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Aug 2008 – Apr 2013 BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Ton Duc Thang University – Vietnam

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Languages English: TOEIC 745 and IELTS 6.0

## Communication skills

Good communication skills gained through my experience as:

- A data analyst: interpersonal skills, able to deliver ideas to coworkers effectively in meetings and via e-mails, Skype.
- A business development assistant: external communication skills, able to communicate and deal with partners, clients in order to meet company's demands.

Managerial skills

Lead a team of 2 people in 1 year at Circle K Vietnam.

## Job-related skills

- Social media data analytics: skilled at analyzing data, generating insights and building reports.
- Marketing: able to conduct marketing campaigns for designated products.

## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# Digital competence

Self-assessment			
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Problem solving
Proficient user	Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user

## (Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user)

- Good command of office suites including products of Microsoft (Word, Excel, Power Point) and Google (Docs, Spreadsheet, Forms, Slides...)
- Good command of social analytics tools: social monitoring, engagement analytics...

## **REFERENCE**

# Ms Nguyen Xuan Hoa

Senior Manager - Global Insight and Analytics

Mobile: 090 395 1025

## **ANNEXES**

List of documents annexed to my CV:

- Cover letter
- Bachelor degree
- **IELTS**, TOEIC certificates

Page 3/3